

Profile

Entrepreneur and team leader for 8 years. Creative Technologist, Product Designer and Frontend Developer. Post-graduated by ESPM in Marketing and Digital Design. Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®). Studying Software Engineering at FIAP. Experienced and passionate about the whole process of building digital products. Specialist in the convergence between business, design and technology.

Employment History

Product Design Lead at Trinks.com, Remote

August 2020 — Present

Biggest marketplace of beauty services in Brazil. More than 700k B2C users and 50k B2B users. Since 2019 part of Stone Group, a payment processing services unicorn.

Responsibilities:

- Collaborate with business, product management, UX designers and engineering partners to lead and develop product and design strategies.
- Advocate for the user, and drive a holistic UX vision that inspires the team to push on the status quo.
- Explore product concepts to find promising directions that address both human and business needs.
- Build prototypes to assist in user research, using low to high-fidelity techniques.
- Support multiple projects simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
- Advise front-end engineers on UI implementation best practices.
- Facilitate collaboration between teams and individuals to evolve the needs of the product alongside the design system.

UI/UX Lead and Cofounder at Interativ, Remote

January 2016 — August 2020

- Problem solver based in user needs and high performance.
- · Team management.
- · Project management.
- Sales of digital solutions.
- User research.
- UI/UX Design.
- Tech lead in UI/UX Development.
- · Integration with rest APIs and GraphQL.
- Javascript Development (Node, Express, Angular, React, Gatsby, Ionic and API integrations).
- PHP, Wordpress, Drupal.
- MySQL, Postgres, mongodb, Redis.

Details

São Paulo Brazil

+5511968884933

byfabioalencar@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn Portfolio Dribble Github

Skills

Design Thinking

UX Research

Interaction Design

Figma

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Prototyping

Design Systems

Agile Project Management

Leadership

Languages

Portuguese

English

Spanish; Castilian

Cofounder and Business Development at Devign, São Paulo

February 2012 — July 2020

- · Design of High Impact Presentations.
- Sales.

Creative Technologist and Fullstack Developer at Universidade Veiga de Almeida (UVA) - Whitney International, Rio de Janeiro

March 2013 — May 2015

- · UI/UX Design.
- Frontend Development (HTML, CSS, Javascript/Jquery).
- Backend Development (PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, Drupal).
- Marketing technologist: Intermediary between Marketing and IT team.

Web designer and Frontend Developer at M2BRNET.com, Rio de Janeiro

April 2011 — May 2012

- Front-End Development (HTML / CSS / JQuery).
- Design of interfaces, newsletters and banners.
- Animation and programming in Action Script 2.0.
- Maintenance, customization and creation of templates for CMS Wordpress.

Frontend Developer at Skidun Interactive Agency, Rio de Janeiro

November 2010 — April 2011

- Front-End Development (HTML / CSS / JQuery).
- · Information architecture.
- Maintenance, customization and creation of templates for CMS Wordpress.

Jr. Web Designer and Frontend Developer at Criapix, Niterói

August 2007 — November 2010

- UI design / Motion Design
- Frontend development (HTML, CSS, JQuery)

Education

Software Engineering - MBA, FIAP, São Paulo

May 2020 — Present

Digital Marketing and Design - MBA, ESPM, Rio de Janeiro

2011 - 2013

Graphic Design, UNESA, Rio de Janeiro

2007 - 2009

Courses

Design System & Ops, Meiuca Design

2020 - 2020

Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®), Scrum Alliance

2020 - 2020

Hello Design Thinking, IDEO U

2020 - 2020

Advanced English Language, Cultura Inglesa

2004 — 2010

Y Extra-curricular activities

Volunteer Staff at Glocal Aceleradora, São Paulo

January 2018 — Present

We encourage social impact agents through a training and support program, which has the potential to transform actions in society.